<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>irunbackwards.com</title>
    <link>http://irunbackwards.com</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 02:07:22 -0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernie 2016</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/bernie-2016</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 01:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/bernie-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the fortunate opportunity to work with the Sanders Campaign and some very talented volunteers to build Connect with Bernie, an official campaign tool designed to coordinate real, targeted action and help win the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an individual contributor, I coordinated with the rest of the team via Pivotal Tracker and Slack to implement functionality and fix bugs in the web application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ubuntu on a Nexus 7 (2012/grouper)</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/installing-ubuntu-nexus-7-2012-grouper</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/installing-ubuntu-nexus-7-2012-grouper</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an old Nexus 7 tablet (original, from 2012) lying around collecting dust, progressively getting slower with each and every Android operating system update. Personally, I find it difficult to part with technology before its true, functional end-of-life. Since the Nexus 7 is a pretty powerful machine, and the resale value is considerably low, I decided to try to put it to good use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume some basic familiarity (meaning it&amp;rsquo;s installed already) with the Android platform tools, namely adb and fastboot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEF/RAW to JPEG Conversion Using OS X&#39;s Automator</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/labs/nef-raw-to-jpeg-conversion-using-os-x-automator</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/labs/nef-raw-to-jpeg-conversion-using-os-x-automator</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spree Pigment</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/spree-pigment</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 05:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/spree-pigment</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZURB Foundation</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/zurb-foundation</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 05:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/zurb-foundation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zurb/foundation/pull/3260&quot;&gt;https://github.com/zurb/foundation/pull/3260&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanthology</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/humanthology</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/humanthology</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position&lt;/strong&gt;: Lead Frontend Developer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July of 2013, I left the comfort of warm Southern California to join a startup in Silicon Valley that was focusing on creating a platform that curated and highlighted the human experience. Humanthology wanted to give a soapbox to the generally unheard and foster a sense of community we seem to be falling out of touch with. I was excited to share in that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanthology was at the forefront of the race to be the next &amp;ldquo;new age&amp;rdquo; publication platform. As lead frontend developer, I crafted and implemented a user experience befitting the modern day of multimedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on inspiration from meticulously tailored, beautiful articles such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall/#/?part=tunnel-creek&quot;&gt;Snow Fall: The Avalanche at Tunnel Creek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/features/cover-story/reader/daft-punk/&quot;&gt;Pitchfork&amp;rsquo;s Daft Punk Cover Story&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.complex.com/covers/danny-brown-interview-sky-high-2013-cover-story/&quot;&gt;Danny Brown Interview: Sky High&lt;/a&gt;. We set out to provide this level of content publishing to the common author, to Joe Schmoe WordPress blog operator &amp;ndash; parallax, HTML5 video, CSS animation, image carousels, the whole kit and kaboodle! These have become intrinsic to the way we share information on the internet and no one should have a barrier to use such constructs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also implemented crowdfunding functionality on the platform. As an author, you could publish a story with a crowdfunding goal. When that goal was reached, the total would be split between the author and a non-profit organization of their choice, usually an organization related to the story itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanthology&amp;rsquo;s growth was overshadowed by similar platforms with larger teams and venture capital backing, specifically Medium. It remained in a nascent state until the platform was retired in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RateMyHospital®</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/ratemyhospital</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 01:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/ratemyhospital</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RateMyHospital® is a HIPAA-secure, mobile and web-based feedback tool that allows hospitals to collect patient feedback and experience in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educate 2 Envision</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/educate-2-envision</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/educate-2-envision</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barterball</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/barterball</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/barterball</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://barterball.com&quot;&gt;Barterball&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;sharing economy&amp;rdquo; platform that facilitates service-for-service trading between locals. My company, Thinglet, was contracted to architect and engineer the minimum viable product so that they could pilot the service. Barterball has since gone on to be acquired as a strategic investment by a Canadian technology company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.altrichmond.ca/index.html&quot;&gt;Alt Richmond&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recon API</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/recon-api</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 01:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/recon-api</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recon API began as a passion project trying to ease the pains of communication between indie app developers and frustrated users. Its intent was to convert negative reviews on Google Play (and eventually, the App Store) into meaningful insight collected via integration with Recon API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was built over a weekend and launched the following Monday. It was used in almost all of the Android applications published by Thinglet, and saw some traction in the Android developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hightlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sourced and helped produce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/33765887&quot;&gt;Recon API intro video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned (barely) enough Java in one weekend to throw together the Android SDK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fvel Me</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/fvel-me</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/fvel-me</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinglet</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/thinglet</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/thinglet</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3KB</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/diablo-3-knowledge-base</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/diablo-3-knowledge-base</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
