<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>irunbackwards.com</title>
    <link>http://irunbackwards.com</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 07:46:24 -0700</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hacker Manifesto</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/the-hacker-manifesto</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 08:23:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/the-hacker-manifesto</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published as &lt;a href=&quot;http://phrack.org/issues/7/3.html#article&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Conscience of a Hacker&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in Phrack by The Mentor &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loyd_Blankenship&quot;&gt;(Loyd Blankenship)&lt;/a&gt; on January 8, 1986.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another one got caught today, it&amp;rsquo;s all over the papers.  &amp;ldquo;Teenager Arrested in Computer Crime Scandal&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Hacker Arrested after Bank Tampering&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Damn kids. They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But did you, in your three-piece psychology and 1950&amp;rsquo;s technobrain, ever take a look behind the eyes of the hacker?  Did you ever wonder what made him tick, what forces shaped him, what may have molded him?&lt;br&gt;
I am a hacker, enter my world&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Mine is a world that begins with school&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m smarter than most of the other kids, this crap they teach us bores me&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Damn underachiever.  They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in junior high or high school.  I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to teachers explain for the fifteenth time how to reduce a fraction.  I understand it.  &amp;ldquo;No, Ms. Smith, I didn&amp;rsquo;t show my work.  I did it in my head&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
Damn kid.  Probably copied it.  They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a discovery today.  I found a computer.  Wait a second, this is cool.  It does what I want it to.  If it makes a mistake, it&amp;rsquo;s because I screwed it up.  Not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t like me&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
  Or feels threatened by me&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
  Or thinks I&amp;rsquo;m a smart ass&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
  Or doesn&amp;rsquo;t like teaching and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be here&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Damn kid.  All he does is play games.  They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then it happened&amp;hellip; a door opened to a world&amp;hellip; rushing through the phone line like heroin through an addict&amp;rsquo;s veins, an electronic pulse is sent out, a refuge from the day-to-day incompetencies is sought&amp;hellip; a board is found.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;This is it&amp;hellip; this is where I belong&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
I know everyone here&amp;hellip; even if I&amp;rsquo;ve never met them, never talked to them, may never hear from them again&amp;hellip; I know you all&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Damn kid.  Tying up the phone line again.  They&amp;rsquo;re all alike&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You bet your ass we&amp;rsquo;re all alike&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve been spoon-fed baby food at school when we hungered for steak&amp;hellip; the bits of meat that you did let slip through were pre-chewed and tasteless.  We&amp;rsquo;ve been dominated by sadists, or ignored by the apathetic.  The few that had something to teach found us willing pupils, but those few are like drops of water in the desert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our world now&amp;hellip; the world of the electron and the switch, the beauty of the baud.  We make use of a service already existing without paying for what could be dirt-cheap if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t run by profiteering gluttons, and you call us criminals.  We explore&amp;hellip; and you call us criminals.  We seek after knowledge&amp;hellip; and you call us criminals.  We exist without skin color, without nationality, without religious bias&amp;hellip; and you call us criminals. You build atomic bombs, you wage wars, you murder, cheat, and lie to us and try to make us believe it&amp;rsquo;s for our own good, yet we&amp;rsquo;re the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am a criminal.  My crime is that of curiosity.  My crime is that of judging people by what they say and think, not what they look like. My crime is that of outsmarting you, something that you will never forgive me for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a hacker, and this is my manifesto.  You may stop this individual, but you can&amp;rsquo;t stop us all&amp;hellip; after all, we&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+++The Mentor+++&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bernie 2016</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/bernie-2016</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 18:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/bernie-2016</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the fortunate opportunity to work with the Sanders Campaign and some very talented volunteers to build Connect with Bernie, an official campaign tool designed to coordinate real, targeted action and help win the 2016 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an individual contributor, I coordinated with the rest of the team via Pivotal Tracker and Slack to implement functionality and fix bugs in the web application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/a-new-hope</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/blog/a-new-hope</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past year has been one of tremendous change and growth, both for myself and the world. In this first post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take the opportunity to share some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, worked on (successes and failures), and am looking forward to accomplishing in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 12, 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Decided to embrace a vegan lifestyle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 1, 2015&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Established a regular exercise routine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I would like to broaden my horizons in a few areas that have always been of interest to me, but never pursued in any routine fashion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I am challenging myself to consistently draw this year, and maybe learn a new style or two. As always, take more pictures in more places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When I was younger, I always had my nose in a book. Now, most of the material I consume is shorter form: news, blog or online publication content, etc. I recently subscribed to Audible and have been averaging 1 book a month so far, which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy about. (Please, send your recommendations!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I am going to write more, a lot more. I registered The Advocateur and The Collecteur and plan to publish content in a consistent manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I want to establish a practice of yoga for myself. It&amp;rsquo;s something that I&amp;rsquo;ve done here and there in the past, but never regularly. I know how hugely valuable it could be to me and the time is now to tap into that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEF/RAW to JPEG Conversion Using OS X&#39;s Automator</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/labs/nef-raw-to-jpeg-conversion-using-os-x-automator</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 23:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/labs/nef-raw-to-jpeg-conversion-using-os-x-automator</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spree Pigment</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/spree-pigment</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 22:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/spree-pigment</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZURB Foundation</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/zurb-foundation</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 22:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/zurb-foundation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zurb/foundation/pull/3260&quot;&gt;https://github.com/zurb/foundation/pull/3260&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humanthology</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/humanthology</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 19:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/humanthology</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position&lt;/strong&gt;: Lead Frontend Developer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July of 2013, I left the comfort of warm Southern California to join a startup in Silicon Valley that was focusing on creating a platform that curated and highlighted the human experience. Humanthology wanted to give a soapbox to the generally unheard and foster a sense of community we seem to be falling out of touch with. I was excited to share in that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanthology was at the forefront of the race to be the next &amp;ldquo;new age&amp;rdquo; publication platform. As lead frontend developer, I crafted and implemented a user experience befitting the modern day of multimedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on inspiration from meticulously tailored, beautiful articles such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall/#/?part=tunnel-creek&quot;&gt;Snow Fall: The Avalanche at Tunnel Creek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://pitchfork.com/features/cover-story/reader/daft-punk/&quot;&gt;Pitchfork&amp;rsquo;s Daft Punk Cover Story&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.complex.com/covers/danny-brown-interview-sky-high-2013-cover-story/&quot;&gt;Danny Brown Interview: Sky High&lt;/a&gt;. We set out to provide this level of content publishing to the common author, to Joe Schmoe WordPress blog operator &amp;ndash; parallax, HTML5 video, CSS animation, image carousels, the whole kit and kaboodle! These have become intrinsic to the way we share information on the internet and no one should have a barrier to use such constructs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also implemented crowdfunding functionality on the platform. As an author, you could publish a story with a crowdfunding goal. When that goal was reached, the total would be split between the author and a non-profit organization of their choice, usually an organization related to the story itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanthology&amp;rsquo;s growth was overshadowed by similar platforms with larger teams and venture capital backing, specifically Medium. It remained in a nascent state until the platform was retired in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RateMyHospital®</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/ratemyhospital</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/ratemyhospital</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RateMyHospital® is a HIPAA-secure, mobile and web-based feedback tool that allows hospitals to collect patient feedback and experience in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educate 2 Envision</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/educate-2-envision</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/educate-2-envision</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barterball</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/barterball</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/barterball</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://barterball.com&quot;&gt;Barterball&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;sharing economy&amp;rdquo; platform that facilitates service-for-service trading between locals. My company, Thinglet, was contracted to architect and engineer the minimum viable product so that they could pilot the service. Barterball has since gone on to be acquired as a strategic investment by a Canadian technology company, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.altrichmond.ca/index.html&quot;&gt;Alt Richmond&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recon API</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/recon-api</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/recon-api</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recon API began as a passion project trying to ease the pains of communication between indie app developers and frustrated users. Its intent was to convert negative reviews on Google Play (and eventually, the App Store) into meaningful insight collected via integration with Recon API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was built over a weekend and launched the following Monday. It was used in almost all of the Android applications published by Thinglet, and saw some traction in the Android developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hightlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sourced and helped produce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/33765887&quot;&gt;Recon API intro video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learned (barely) enough Java in one weekend to throw together the Android SDK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fvel Me</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/fvel-me</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/fvel-me</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinglet</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/thinglet</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 17:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/thinglet</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3KB</title>
      <link>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/diablo-3-knowledge-base</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>Nuri Hodges</author>
      <guid>http://irunbackwards.com/portfolio/diablo-3-knowledge-base</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
